Guide to the Roberta Price Papers and Photographs
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Roberta Price papers and photographs
1965-2013
WA MSS S-3208
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
11.12
(11 boxes)
The collection consists of photographs taken by Roberta Price of communes in the southwestern United States from 1969 to 1970, including black and white and color prints, negatives, and transparencies. The collection also includes drafts, correspondence, and printed material relating to Huerfano: A Memoir of Life in the Counterculture; additional photographs; interviews and other born digital audiovisual materials; and other papers.
Price, Roberta
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of photographs taken by Roberta Price of communes in the southwestern United States from 1969 to 1970, including black and white and color prints, negatives, and transparencies. The collection also includes drafts, correspondence, and printed material relating to Huerfano: A Memoir of Life in the Counterculture; additional photographs; interviews and other born digital audiovisual materials; and other papers.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Roberta Price on the Frederick W. and Carrie S. Beinecke Fund for Western Americana, 2013.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 10 (digital media) and box 11 (videocassettes): Restricted fragile material. Access copies of may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Roberta Price
Roberta Price is a photographer, writer, and intellectual property attorney in Albuquerque, New Mexico. In 2004 the University of Massachusetts Press published Huerfano: A Memoir of Life in the Counterculture, based on Price's experience living in communes in the southwestern United States in the late 1960s and 1970s.
Arrangement
Arranged roughly in the order in which the collection was received.
Communal living -- United States; Photographers -- United States -- Archives; West (U.S.) -- Pictorial works; Audiovisual materials; Born digital; Film negatives; Photographs; Photographers -- United States -- 20th Century; Price, Roberta
- Peter Coyote interview, list, 2013 (Box 1)
  Separated Materials
  1 flash drive removed for separate housing.
  - Peter Coyote interview, 2013; 1 (Box 10)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
- Exceptional Women of the Counterculture, circa 2000s; 1 (Box 10)
- "RMP Beinecke Additional #1, #2, #3", circa 2000s; 3 (Box 10)
- "Across the Great Divide (book photos)," envelope, circa 2000s (Box 1)
  2 DVDs removed for separate housing.
  - "Across the Great Divide (book photos)", circa 2000s; 2 (Box 10)
- Across the Great Divide, by Roberta Price - proof, 2010 (Box 1)
- Huerfano, by Roberta Price - uncorrected proof, 2004 (Box 1)
- "Communal Living" - photographs and contact prints, undated (Box 1)
- "Communal Living" - photographs and text, undated; 3 folders (Box 1)
- "Communal Living" - photographs, undated (Box 1)
- "Communal Living" - negatives and contact prints, 1969-1970 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Includes material relating to: Zoar Valley, Buffalo (1969-1970); Washington D.C. and Buffalo; University of California, Berkeley; Frank Reed wedding photographs (1970).
- "Communal Living" - negatives and contact prints, 1969 (Box 1)
  Includes material relating to: Drop City, Summer '69; New Buffalo and Reality, Summer '69; Libre, Summer '69.
- "Communal Living" - negatives and contact prints, 1970 (Box 1)
  Includes material relating to: Summer '70; R.R. Struts party; early house construction; tipi site, etc.
- "Communal Living" - negatives and contact prints, 1970 (Box 1)
  Includes material relating to: Libre (1970); Lama Foundation (1970); Reality Construction; Placitas domes, etc.
- "Communal Living" - slides, undated (Box 1)
  Includes material relating to: University of Massachusetts; Huerfano.
- "Communal Living" - slides, 1969-1971; 4 folders (Box 1)
- "Communal Living" - printouts of photographs, 1969-1970 (Box 2)
- Slides, undated; 5 folders (Box 2)
- "Book Photos" - photograph thumbnail print-outs and slides, undated (Box 2)
  1 DVD removed for separate housing.
  - "Book Photos", circa 2009; 1 (Box 10)
- "Book Photos" - photographic prints, undated; 2 folders (Box 2)
- Huerfano - photographs, undated (Box 2)
- Huerfano - cover proof and "photos not used", 2006 (Box 2)
- Huerfano - drafts, circa 2002; 9 folders (Box 3)
- Huerfano - drafts, circa 2002; 3 folders (Box 4)
- Huerfano - UMASS correspondence, 2003-2007 (Box 5)
- Huerfano - correspondence, 2003-2008 (Box 5)
- "Huerfano PR, radio interviews" - envelopes, 2005 (Box 5)
  3 CDs and 2 CD-Rs removed for separate housing.
  - "Huerfano PR, radio interviews", 2005; 3; 2 (Box 10)
- Huerfano - notes, 2003-2004 (Box 5)
- Allen Ginsberg - "Plutonian Ode", circa 1980 (Box 5)
- Huerfano - Jack Weiss, 2003 (Box 5)
- Roberta, Huerfano - email printouts, circa 2000s (Box 5)
- Huerfano - David Perkins edits, 1997-2003 (Box 5)
- "David" - magazines and printed material, 1969-1995 (Box 5)
- Naropa Institute, undated (Box 5)
- Huerfano - Vassar "Time Out" Grant, circa 2000 (Box 5)
- Index to Helene Wurlitzer Foundation of New Mexico Application - Roberta M. Price, 1991 (Box 5)
- Huerfano - typescript proof, 2004 (Box 5)
- Huerfano - Communal Societies review, photocopy, 2005 (Box 5)
- Huerfano - Bookworks talks, flyers, circa 2007 (Box 5)
- Huerfano - Page One bookstore, 2005 (Box 5)
- Huerfano - "Denver Tattered Cover 1/19/05", 2004 (Box 5)
- Huerfano - New York trip, 2005 (Box 5)
- Huerfano - Phoenix, 2005 (Box 5)
- Huerfano - Palm Springs book festival, 2005 (Box 5)
- Huerfano - "Austin Reading June 7th," and "The Twig" newsletter, 2005 (Box 5)
- Huerfano - Book People events, 2005 (Box 5)
- Huerfano - Vassar, 2005 (Box 5)
- Huerfano - The New Mexican, clippings, 2004 (Box 5)
- Huerfano - Newark Star-Ledger, clipping, circa 2005 (Box 5)
- Huerfano - Oregon Weekly, 2005 (Box 5)
- Huerfano - Tempo Magazine / The Taos News, 2005 (Box 5)
- Huerfano - UNM Law School magazine, 2004 (Box 5)
- Huerfano - Colorado Central magazine, 2005 (Box 5)
- Huerfano - Forward magazine, 2004 (Box 5)
- Huerfano - Los Angeles Times Book Review, print-out, 2004 (Box 5)
- Huerfano - Alibi, 2004 (Box 5)
- Huerfano - [Atlantic City] Press, photocopy, 2005 (Box 5)
- Huerfano - Austin-American Statesman, 2005 (Box 5)
- Huerfano - Around 505 magazine, 2005 (Box 5)
- Huerfano - Albuquerque Journal clippings, 2004 (Box 5)
- Huerfano - Albuquerque Tribune clippings, 2004 (Box 5)
- Huerfano - Alibi clippings and photocopies, 2004 (Box 5)
- Huerfano - Vanity Fair, 2004 (Box 5)
- Huerfano - Vassar Alumni Magazine, 2002-2004 (Box 5)
- Huerfano - Westword, 2005 (Box 5)
- Huerfano - Albuquerque Journal, 1999 (Box 5)
- Huerfano - Los Angeles Times, 1999 (Box 5)
- Huerfano - Zia articles and New York Times clippings, 1999-2000 (Box 5)
- Huerfano - Ms. magazine, 1974 (Box 5)
- Huerfano - The Signature newspaper, 2012 (Box 5)
- Huerfano proposal and Huerfano draft, 2003 (Box 6)
- Huerfano - first draft, circa 2003 (Box 6)
- Huerfano - draft, 2003; 3 folders (Box 6)
- Huerfano - UMASS 12/04/03 draft, 2003; 3 folders (Box 6)
- Huerfano - hand-written notes, circa 2000-2001 (Box 6)
- Huerfano - draft, pages 231-456, circa 2003 (Box 6)
- Huerfano - questions from Austin U.T. students, 2008 (Box 6)
- Brick Magazine - correspondence and print-outs, 2013 (Box 6)
- SouthWest Writers contest - Huerfano entry, 2001 (Box 6)
- "Across the Great Divide" and "Huerfano" - printed reviews, 2010-2011 (Box 6)
- Huerfano - artist biography, correspondence and "Across the Great Divide" exhibit, circa 2011 (Box 6)
- "Magic Bus: On the Hippie Trail from Istanbul to India," book review, 2009 (Box 6)
- Counter-culture newspapers, 1966-1970 (Box 6)
- University of New Mexico Press, Fall 2011 and exhibition catalog for "Across the Great Divide" (Box 6)
- Vanity Fair magazine, 2010 (Box 6)
- "History Colorado" lectures brochure and The Richard L. Nelson Gallery leaflet regarding "Across the Great Divide", 2011 (Box 6)
- "Across the Great Divide" exhibition catalog and various leaflets, 2011 (Box 6)
- Across the Great Divide - University of New Mexico Press leaflet and correspondence, 2011 (Box 6)
- Huerfano - proposal and draft, 2002 (Box 6)
- Huerfano - proposal and first chapter draft, undated (Box 6)
- Newspapers and clippings, circa 2010-2011 (Box 7)
- Uncommon Ground, exhibition poster, 2011 (Box 7)
- "Shelter," publication, 1973 (Box 7)
- Life Magazine, Woodstock Music Festival: Special Edition, 1969 (Box 8)
- "Huerfano Map" and associated artwork, circa 2004 (Box 9 (Oversize))
- "Huerfano Map," New Mexico by [M.S. Moore], circa 2004 (Box 9 (Oversize))
- Huerfano, color poster, 2005 (Box 9 (Oversize))
- Audiovisual Material
  Audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Roberta Price, 516 gallery, tape 1, undated; 1; 01:03:46 (Box 11, Item barcode 39002104889929)
    Box 11 (audiovisual material): Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Roberta Price from PZ, 516 gallery, tape 2, undated; 1; 00:47:36 (Box 11, Item barcode 39002093778653)